[Music]
good morning and happy monday to you
this is stocks to watch on bloomberg
quint and i'm alex matthew apologies for
the delay
we had a bit of a technical snag in the
morning my guest today is avinash
gorakshakar of profit mart the first uh
you know of the three stocks in focus uh
today avinash
is icici lombard general insurance the
company has gotten into an agreement to
acquire the
non-life operations of bharti axa
general insurance
first of all how would you rate this
deal how do you see playing out for icsa
lombard
and would you buy at the current level
and also good morning to you
yeah morning alex and apologies for the
technical delay
uh as far as i say lombard is concerned
i think it definitely appears to be
a very positive kind of development our
sense is that
you know in the first year this deal
will definitely be slightly
earnings dilutive but from a longer term
perspective definitely it adds a lot of
value to
icsa lombard the stock should possibly
positively open today because
the street was definitely okay
um well we've lost uh avinash's audio
temporarily hopefully we can get him
back but
he was talking yeah i don't know if he
lost your audio temporarily
uh you were saying that it's going to be
it's going to take a little time for it
to be earning the credit
okay we seem to be having a bit of an
issue with
avinash's line but avinash you were
talking about the fact that it's going
to take a little time for the
uh merger to be earning the credit right
yeah i think uh it may not be earning
secretive from the first year alex
i mean
okay uh seemingly we're having a lot of
trouble with this
line as of now but just to take you
through
the key highlight of that deal there is
going to be a swap
agreement between icici lombard and
bharti actually
happening only
okay we're going to try and sort this
issue out but
in the meanwhile bharti access
shareholders are going to get two icici
lombard shares for every 115
held in bharti accent the total annual
premium of the combined entity expected
to be
at least 16 500 crore or thereabouts and
the the market share of the combined
entity is going to come in at around 8.7
let me check in with avinash to see if
he's back
online and if he is uh avinash can you
hear me now
yeah i can hear you alex okay so very
sh let's keep it short and simple then
is this going to be a positive
for uh for ics lombard and would you buy
at the current level
yeah i think uh it is a positive
development alex and i think
earnings declaration could start from
the second year onwards so i think
despite the fact that first year
it may not be earning secretive but
longer term i think one could definitely
look at this business
since we believe that longer term you
know ics and lombard has a great
future and the risk reward could turn
better over the longer term
all right avenues the second stock we're
talking about india bulls housing
finance and it seems the india bulls
group as a whole is going through a bit
of a transition as of now
the earnings were announced over the
weekend which were quite bad from what i
can see the net profit down 66 percent
net interest income down over 50 percent
there's a widening in the bad loans
which now start
at 2.2 percent and talking about vnpa
but i thought the commentary was
interesting the company says it plans to
grow its balance sheet by seven to eight
percent
uh and it's a um by twelve percent and
it says it says that its
phase of reduction of its loan book and
eom is
over and there's also the fact that uh
deputy governor of the rbi former
uh mudra has taken over at the helm how
should one look at this
would you buy the current level uh i
think alex
definitely positive you know news flows
coming from the company in terms of the
management change
some restructuring announced our senses
you know
these numbers definitely look quite
encouraging from the management
commentary but i think the markets and
we believe that you know it would take
at least one to two quarters before
all this could get reflected into
numbers so i think uh i would definitely
prefer to hold on
fresh buying could possibly be done only
when
some these numbers get reflected into
financials and i would not be surprised
the market would also
give it a you know wait and watch kind
of approach so net net i think
definitely this is positive but longer
term i think for the picture to correct
and some trajectory to happen
it could take the next six to eight
months
hmm in fact off the financial pack
this is one stock uh that has gotten
battered very
significantly uh when that major
correction happened sometime last
year the last stock that we have to talk
about is in fact the stock that has been
in focus
last week it gained as much as 60
percent
uh in the last five trading sessions or
so we're talking about va tech wahbag
and and it's interesting to note that
the stock has recovered significantly in
the year to date period
and it's now trading at very close to
what it was trading at
about a year before now but what is
interesting
and hopefully avinash is online with me
right now
is the fact that there hasn't been a
major fundamental development
to justify or to give a reason for
this massive rise in the share price
that you can see right now
avinash you know without getting into
the details of why the share price
increase has happened because we can't
possibly tell that right now
you look at the fundamentals and tell us
how would you rate the stock
as it stands right now
well i think alex the rice seems to be
purely speculative i think uh the first
quarter numbers for
fy21 have also not been encouraging
almost flat
pat numbers of almost 30 crores but what
is interesting is that
as of march 2020 uh you know this
company recorded a top line of almost
2500 crores out of which 1600 crores are
yet
locked in debtors so the cash flow
continues to be quite weak and our sense
is that
unless the company makes a genuine
effort in improving its operating cash
flow and you know reduces its uh getters
in the pipeline uh this stock uh
going forward is not going to be
significantly related from these levels
so i think one has to be careful
uh yes the order book is very strong 11
000 odd close but i think
uh execution and the working capital uh
you know management issues uh would be
key focus area so i would prefer to wait
for one of the one or two quarters
uh and then you know take a closer look
at the company but overall i think
uh it seems that you know more of
speculative activity has you know pushed
the stock
uh to these levels at least in the near
term that's the picture which is coming
across
all right uh avinash i i'm not going to
take a chance by asking another question
because we might lose the link as it
stands right now thank you so much for
joining me
uh today and uh despite all the
disruptions i think my power for the
course 2020 has been challenging
uh so thanks so much for joining me
again uh and to you dear viewers thank
you so much for
uh bearing with us a bit of a technical
issue this morning
do stay tuned there's a lot more coming
up in just a short while
you